## DIPAK SHAMRAO HEDAU (1) Featured

MCA with 4.5 yeas Of Experience in Jave Development, Senior Java Developer, Senior Software Engineer



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Nelito System Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Navi Mumbai Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Agile Methodology, Server Management, HTML, CSS, SQL Server, Spring Boot, Spring, Mvc, Spring, Java, Hibernate, Microservices, Spring

Integration, J2Ee, JPA, Log4j, Servlets, JSP, Oracle, MySQL, Javascript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

Total 4.5 years of IT experience in design, development, implementation and testing of Client-Server, Web Applications using Java/J2EE Technologies.

Experience in SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) that includes Requirements Analysis, Design, Coding, Testing, Implementation, Maintenance with methodologies like Waterfall Model and Agile Methodology. Experience in design and development of web-based applications using Java, JDBC, SQL, Servlets, JSTL, JSP, XML, Java-API and Spring MVC, Spring Boot.

Expertise on Core Java Technologies like Multithreading, Collections and Exception handling mechanisms. Experience in client side Technologies such as HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript and Jquery, AJAX, JSON. Experience with the ORM tool like Hibernate involving Mappings, Transaction Management, HQL (Hibernate Query Language)

Experience in implementing SOA (Service Oriented Architecture) using Web Services (SOAP, WSDL, Restful, and JAX-WS) and REST Services.

## Work Experience

Nelito System as Senior Software Engineer Sep 2019 to Till Date

Specially Working in Banking And Finance is domain

Fino Payement Bank pvt. Ltd. as Software Developer Nov 2017 to Aug 2019

Specially Working in Banking And Finance is domain

TelezenWeb Pvt. Ltd. as Java Developer Jul 2016 to Nov 2017

#### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from Nagpur University in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from Nagpur University in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Spring and Hibernate

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
core Java, advance java			
J2EE, Collection Framework			
Multithreading, Web Services			
REST, SOAP,JDBC, JSP, JSTL			
Servlets, HTML/HTML 5			
CSS/CSS3, JavaScript			
Jquery, Ajax			
XML, JSON			
Spring Framework, Spring MVC			
Spring Boot , Hibernate, JPA			
Oracle Web-logic 12c			
IBM WebSphere 9.0			
Redhat JBoss 6.0 , Apache Tomcat 7/8			
SQL Server 2012,Oracle 10g, MySQL			
Eclipse Kepler, Neon, Oxygen			
Net-beans 8.0			
WinSCP, SVN , PVCS			
Windows 7/10, Linux, Unix			
Singleton, Factory, MVC			
SOLID,DRY, Algorithms			
Agile, Waterfall, Scrum			
IBM Content Navigator			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Marathi	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
English	Proficient			

### **Projects**

Project Title: DataCap Client: State Bank of India Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 Role: Sr. Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role Description: Designing, implementing, and maintaining Java applications that are often high-volume and low-latency, required for mission-critical systems.

? Understand Solution documents, Code Development, Client interaction

Project Details: DataCap is a Specially use for Storing the scan document in the database and upload that document to CKYC teams through API.

? DataCap Appliacation use SSO Authentication for LogIn.

? Following are some module in Datacap.

1. SSO Authentication for LogIN

- 2. Upload New Document through webservice.
- 3. Scan New Document through Scanner which is internally connected to dataCap application.
- 4. LCPC Rejection Module through Webservice.

Project Title: NPS

Client: State Bank of India Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2019 - Jun 2020 Project Location: Nerul, Navi Mumbai Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer

Role Description: Designing, implementing, and maintaining Java applications that are often high-volume and low-latency, required for mission-critical systems.

? Understand Solution documents, Code Development, Client interaction

Project Details: National Pension System (NPS) is a contributory pension system whereby contributions from subscribers along with matching contributions from respective governments as an employer are collected and accumulated in an individual pension account of the employee.

? NPS uses a system of Government/ Autonomous Bodies? Nodal offices, a Central Record keeping Agency (CRA) and designated Pension Funds (PFs), as specified by the respective regulations to achieve synergy and maximum efficiency in operations.

? NPS-NSDL Straight-through Processing ("STP") is a mechanism that automates the end-to-end processing of transactions of the financial instruments (Registration and Contribution in NPS and APY).

Project Title: DMS

Client: FINO Payments Bank Limited Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Nerul, Navi Mumbai

Role: Programmer

Role Description: Designing, implementing, and maintaining Java applications that are often high-volume and low-latency, required for mission-critical systems.

Duration: Nov 2017 - Aug 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

? Delivering high availability and performance.

? Writing well-designed, efficient, and testable code.

Project Details: DMS is Document management system which will store the data and document of customer which will open the account in bank and all other information.

? The DMS is totlly working on product and using this product we will store the data in database There are 7 module in DMS.

? Account Opening, Kit Management, Customer Grievance, Service Request, Lending Account ? Banking Domain project connected with CBS and All Other Record keeping Agencies In India

Project Title: Hospital Management System

Client: Gaikwad Hospital

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2016 - Nov 2017 Project Location: Nagpur Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer

Project Details: Hospital Management System is Management project in which is used to the data of patient. includes registration of patients, storing their details into the system, and also computerized billing in the pharmacy, and labs.

? Our software has the facility to give a unique id for every patient and stores thedetails of every patient and the staff automatically.

? It includes a search facility to know the current status of each room.

? User can search availability of a doctor and the details of a patient using the id.

Project Title: Shop Management System

Client: Balaji Garments

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2016 - Nov 2017 Project Location: Nagpur Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer

Project Details: Shop management System and designs for the delivery, distribution, storage, collection, and removal of occupant-generated streams of materials and services.

- ? The Shop Management system controls the whole chain of material from its Purchase requirement to the delivery of material to concerneddepartment.
- ? Software is use for inventory management also for stock and other calculationwill automatically calculated.
- ? Specially design for GST Calculation.

Project Title: Real Estate Project Client: Shreekrishna developer Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Nahpur

Role: Programmer

e of Employment: Full Time

t Location: Nahpur

Duration: Jul 2016 - Nov 2017
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Real Estate management System designs for Real Estate in which we will maintain the data of all client related to booking and all the record of client related to plot and flat purchase and rent.

- ? The Real Estate management controls the whole chain of estate from its Purchase requirement to the delivery of estate to Respective customer.
- ? Software is use Maintaining the record of customer related to purchase and rent.
- ? Specially design for GST Calculation.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time